Rinat Sabitov

- Kazan, Russia
- +7 927 491 99 67
- rinat.sabitov@gmail.com
- https://false.org.ru

Briefly about me. I've been doing web development in Python for more than 8 years. I am a server-side guy but I also know how client-side stuff works. I am one of the founders and organizers of DevDay IT community in Kazan city. I make some contribution into OpenStack Liberty. I'm a maintainer of commonly use python library for a CouchDB.

Education

Master's degree, Kazan State Technical University named after A. N. Tupolev, 2004 – 2009 automated-systems, software-engineering

Specialization: computer and automatic systems software

Work Experience

Python Developer, Cloud Linux Kernelcare, May 2018 - Current [Remote]

python, jenkins, grafana, graphite, clickhouse, ansible, InfluxDB, telegraf

Progress:

• Log analyzing tools

- Third-party products integrations
- Participating in a python developers grading committee

Python Developer, Cloud Linux Kuberdock, March 2016 - May 2018 [Remote]

python, kubernetes, docker, ansible, ceph, redis, twisted, amazon-web-services, buildbot, packer, jenkins, golang Progress:

- Implemented developer environment deployment scripts
- Complex backup scripts
- Gradual upgrade system from scratch
- Maintaining a distributed Linux packages build system.
- Automated images build system (AWS, OpenNebula, Vagrant, and others)
- Holding technical interviews python developers

Python Developer, ASD Technologies, June 2015 - March 2016

 $open stack,\ an sible,\ docker,\ python,\ amqp,\ rabbitmq,\ amazon-web-services,\ fuse,\ celery$

Progress:

- Applying OpenStack Mistral component for internal usage.
- Writing instances backup workflow scripts using YAQL.
- Writing dashboards for OpenStack Horizon covering mistral component API.
- Writing devstack deploying scripts for the vagrant.
- Deploying OpenStack components on docker with ansible.
- Applying AMQP realizations for systems components interoperability.
- FUSE implementation for caching some disk operations.

Senior Developer, BARS Group, November 2010 - May 2015

 $python,\ django,\ scrum,\ extjs4,\ celery,\ nginx,\ nsis,\ postgresql,\ soap,\ xml,\ architecture$

Full life circle Django RIA development. Participating in several high-load projects for a government (The Ministry of Education) as maintainer and development from scratch. I led the development department. First attempts to implement Agile methodology and code review. Tried to get more points in the Joel test (8 so far).

Progress:

- integration with Russian E-Government infrastructures (Unified system of interagency electronic interaction)
- complex b2b integrations, SOAP services, and authorization backends
- streamlined continuous integration process
- · code review
- more than 80% of tests coverage
- complex business logic and reporting server-side implementation
- writing simple ExtJS based user interfaces
- implemented a continuous integration for most of our projects
- written some new components for our platform.

Also:

- internal training and tutorials
- participating in technical interviews with candidates and staff certification

Developer, AkBarsMed, August 2009 – November 2010

delphi, intraweb, firebird

For several years I worked in the health insurance sector, where I developed accounting and information systems. One of these systems serving a population of one state (~3M people). Client-server architecture with Firebird DB server on one side (1000+ stored procedures), and Delphi client on others.

Progress:

- first version control (Subversion) for source code implementation in the department
- first web-applications in the department
- massive refactoring + migrating from Delphi 5 to Delphi 7
- fuzzy mailing addresses recognition based on soundex

er			

Functional Programming Principles in Scala (Coursera), 2014 - 2014

Projects

- py-couchdb python, https://github.com/histrio/py-couchdb Modern pure python CouchDB Client.
- czfrq python, rust, https://github.com/histrio/czfrq Generate anki deck from Czech frequency word list
- rssbook go, https://github.com/histrio/rssbook Set of tools that helps to make a podcast from an audiobook.
- python-descript-ion python, https://github.com/histrio/python-descript-ion Simple library for descript.ion files manipulation
- uchecker python, https://github.com/cloudlinux/kcare-uchecker/ A simple tool to detect outdated shared libraries

Also

secure conversation:

PGP: rinat.sabtiov@gmail.com 4096R/D122293D: 8A98 93D4 B64B 480E 471D BE57 1883 9067 D122 293D